Patrick Pissurno.

Full-stack Software Engineer.

patrick@pissurno.dev + +55 (21) 98121-5141 github.com/patrickpissurno + linkedin.com/in/patrickpissurno + pissurno.dev

Summary Statement

Experienced Software Engineer, B.S. in Computer Science, with 5+ years of experience powering fast-paced startups. Reduced page loading times by 40% and built tools that improved operational efficiency by 30%, which contributed to the company's huge growth during the pandemic (edging out competitors). Seeking an international opportunity to work with talented people and further advance my career. Hi!

Work Experience

Lead Software Engineer, Grupo T.T.

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil April 2018 - Present

- Refactored the ETL pipeline to use AWS Lambda and SNS, allowing for event-based actions and reducing the time it takes for data to move from end to end from several minutes to just a few seconds.
- Restructured the systems to allow them to expand from operating a single brand to four (and beyond) with the same cost and reusing the same infrastructure. The new brands represent an increase in revenue of more than 30%.
- Implemented tools and automated actions that helped with customer retention, which resulted in the NPS increasing by 10%.
- Pioneered the creation of a custom Kitchen Display Service that directly integrates with the iFood API, at a time when there was no public documentation. This allowed for huge improvements to the operation, reducing wait times by 20%, increasing output by 25%, and increasing measured customer satisfaction by 10%.
- Built websites for each one of their brands, using Node.js and Vue with SSR, which cut down loading times by 40% compared to their previous WordPress solution.
- Restructured their systems to allow them to expand into franchising, a huge endeavor to port
 most systems so that franchisees would have access to the same tech that powers their
 success, while keeping the costs to scale low and the data isolated and safe. The venture into
 franchising represented a 3% increase in profit and is projected to grow to 7% by Q1 2023.
- Led the engineering team, mentoring fellow developers, reviewing PRs, and helping them improve and build software that is both clean, maintainable, and scalable.

Full-stack Engineer, PicPromo

São Paulo (Remote), Brazil

August 2018 - December 2019

- Refactored the startup's backend, migrating from Firebase to MySQL and from Express.js to Fastify, which combined led to a 10% cost reduction in the Google Cloud Platform, and a 20% decrease in load times.
- Built their homepage using Vue, Bootstrap 4, CSS Flexbox and Grid. By applying the best practices and optimizations, it managed to achieve a 90+ Google PageSpeed score at the time.
- Built a few custom email templates using MJML, resulting in awesome promotional and transactional email messages.

Full-stack Engineer, Genie App Brasil

Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

September 2016 - September 2017

- Built their app as a solo developer, using native Android (Java) with RxJava2 and Retrofit. It supported social sign-in and push notifications.
- Built their backend as a solo developer, using Node.js (Express.js) and MySQL. Deployed it to DigitalOcean. By following good practices, I managed to keep the initial operational costs minimal, while the backend still provided low response times.

Education

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Computer Science

Fluminense Federal University (UFF), Niterói, Brazil March 2017 - July 2022

Minor in Entrepreneurship and Innovation

Fluminense Federal University (UFF), Niterói, Brazil March 2018 - December 2018

Technical Degree in Game Programming

Advanced Education Center (NAVE), Rio de Janeiro, Brazil February 2014 - December 2016

Skills

Expert (★★★★★): JavaScript, Node.js, Fastify, Vue.js, PostgreSQL, CSS, Git Version Control Advanced (★★★★☆): Android programming (Java), AWS, Redis, C#, Web Scraping, CMS Familiar (★★★☆☆): Flutter, TypeScript, Python, Google Cloud (GCP), DigitalOcean, MongoDB, NGINX

Personal Projects

Android App, MPC Funk 2019

Low-latency drum machine app with Brazilian Funk sound samples. It reached more than 1M downloads on the Google Play Store, reaching the top 3 in its category. Now unpublished due to it requiring some maintenance and my priorities having shifted. It featured AdMob monetization, in-app purchases and I built it using Node.js and native Android (Java).

Languages

- Fluent in English
- Native Portuguese speaker